# Cristiano de Oliveira Faustino

# Software Developer

Victoria, British Columbia - Canada

+1 (250) 516-6800 cristiadu@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

My name is Cristiano, 29 years old, born in Brazil, and currently living in Victoria, British Columbia, Canada. I like to work with various aspects of technology, especially if it involves lines of code and logical reasoning, and I'm always open to learning new things and face new challenges.

Currently, I'm working for Daitan Group as a Software Developer, helping to establish patterns for microservices by providing guidance for my team, developing the software, as well as participating in architectural decisions for the libraries, tools and microservices our team is responsible for.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Daitan Group, British Columbia - Canada** – *Tech Lead / Software Developer* 

April 2019 - Current

- Keep collaborating with a client that is a major communication company located in California/US.
- Providing technical leadership on the Public API team. Participating in architectural discussions of the applications the team was involved, discussing and defining patterns to follow and technologies to use. Also providing hands-on knowledge on the application components, and helping everyone understand what needs to be done in order to achieve the team's goals.
- Currently working on another team created to define patterns of microservice development throughout our product. I work together with other developers on a team which is responsible for libraries, tooling and automation around microservices development within the company, applying patterns and default configurations in a way that re-usage of those settings within micro-services is easily done and maintainable.

#### Daitan Group, British Columbia - Canada - Software Developer

January 2019 - April 2019

- Working on the new site of Daitan Group in Victoria, British Columbia, Canada.
- Helping the new site growth by making the best work I can as a Software Developer, and structuring the new site for further development as well, assisting on both recruitment and infrastructure.
- Keep working as a Software Developer, mostly with the Java language using Spring and Spring Boot frameworks, as well as scripting work with Python and Groovy, and testing using JBehave, JUnit and Robot Framework. Building Public APIs widely available for developers to build integrations from other services with our communication software.

### **Daitan Group, Campinas - Brazil** – *Software Developer*

July 2016 - December 2018

- Working with a client that is a major communication company located in California/US. Daitan serves as a consultancy firm, providing technical knowledge and software development.
- The project I have worked on consists of a communication system that
  is focused on security and end-to-end encryption. The system is built
  on Spring Framework and ReactJS, and it uses a Microservice-based
  infrastructure, with components deployed on both GCP and AWS cloud
  platforms.
- I worked mainly as a Fullstack Developer, with my team being focused on constructing Public APIs that allows apps and other services to communicate with our system.

### **Daitan Group, Campinas - Brazil** – *Software Tester*

January 2016 - June 2016

- Worked with a client that is a major provider for network equipment around the globe.
- Our team responsibilities were mainly test VOIP functionalities of the Optical Network Terminal (ONT) equipment that our client was releasing, assuring that the functionalities on the ONT embedded software were working as expected. The VOIP protocols being used and tested included SIP, MGCP, H.248, among others.

## **Daitan Group, Campinas - Brazil** – Web Development Intern

July 2015 - December 2015

- Our client was a worldwide video and audio conference specialized company that is the leader of a significant part of the European audiovisual conference market.
- The team I was a part of developed and maintained service consumer's unique websites, where each website had a different subdomain for each one of the company's clients, with information on how to connect on the multiple conference systems integrated within that specific client subscribed plan.

# **Tealeris Inc., San Diego - U.S** – Software Development Intern

June 2014 - March 2015

- Tealeris Inc. is a company located in San Diego, California that creates and develops the code for embedded systems solutions focused mostly on mobile access control.
- I implemented the new SMS-Access web system, which allows users to use their cell phone to access electronic gates, providing them an alternative (and secure) way to enter those gates when they lost or forgot their card. It also had an administrative web interface to control users & gate access. It was developed using .NET MVC 5 and SQL Server.

## **UFSCar, São Carlos - Brazil** – *Software Development Intern*

January 2012 - January 2013

- Federal University of S\u00e3o Carlos (UFSCar) is a public federal university of Brazil. It also is where I studied to get my Computer Science BSc. degree.
- My team worked on fixing bugs and giving new features for multiple
   Java based systems (using JSF and Hibernate) inside the university.

# **Digicomm, Santa Barbara D'Oeste - Brazil** – *Software Developer*

November 2010 - March 2011

- Digicomm was a software development consulting company that provided software development for e-commerce stores of our major client from China.
- My team's project consisted of building and maintaining the ERP (Administrative) and CRM (Support) systems that were used by all stores from our clients. We also started the development of a new system for both purposes created from scratch, using Zend Framework (PHP Framework) and ExtJS (Javascript Frontend library).

# Alpphoria, Santa Barbara D'Oeste - Brazil – Software Developer

January 2010 - November 2010

- Alpphoria was a web design focused company that provided Software Development services for another company called For Medical; with the second one focused on building medical equipment for use in hospitals and health centers.
- Our team focused mainly on fixing bugs and developing new features for the administrative system (built on PHP) For Medical used. The system had structure to generate invoices, to control work orders (for support of medical equipment), to control the inventory of equipment and machines, and so on.

#### SKILLS / CERTIFICATIONS / LANGUAGES

- Java (6+ years)
- Spring Framework and Spring Boot (5+ years)
- Git (5+ years)
- SQL (4+ years)
- Javascript (4+ years)
- AWS Cloud Platform (3+ years)
- Scrum (3+ years)
- JUnit, RestAssured and Mockito (3+ years)
- Bash Scripting (3+ years)
- DynamoDB (2+ years)
- Kubernetes (2+ years)
- HTML/CSS (2+ years)
- JBehave (2+ years)
- Python (2+ years)
- Robot Framework (2+ years)
- Google Cloud Platform (1+ years)

#### **EDUCATION**

**UNICAMP –** Software Engineering Specialization

February 2018 - December 2018

Federal University Of São Carlos – BSc Computer Science

March 2011 - December 2015

**University of California, San Diego –** *Exchange Program* 

January 2014 - December 2014

Science Without Borders program provided by the brazilian government.

**Technical College - UNICAMP –** *Technical Degree, Computer Science* 

January 2007 - December 2009